

Mikael Vatau sleepbrunch@gmail. com (000) 111-1111

Address Rua Heliodoro 22a Lisbon Portugal

Mikael Vatau

Software Engineer

About Me Eight years experience developing mobile phone platform and almost 13 year experience in embedded system development both hardware and software. Worked with audio, GPS, touchscreen, Bluetooth, WLAN and motor control in large and small scaled project. Seven years experience in customer care.

Software Development Skills

Programming

C / C++PHPJSJavaShellPython

Computer Software

MySQLLinuxAndroid

Experience

Sep 2017 - Oct 2023, *Technical Support*, Accenture Technical support for Google Adwords and Analytics

Aug 2016 - Oct 2017, *Customer Support*, CGI Portugal Supporting both interal and customer in IT

Sep 2015 - Aug 2019, *Customer Support*, Teleperformance Supporting Swedish customers (Photobox, Boxer)

Mar 2005 - Apr 2019, Software Consultant, Netville AB

I was involved in software configuration, low-level audio development, GPS, touch screen, WLAN, Bluetooth, on-site technical support, and application development during my 8-year tenure at Netville:

- Camera Web Interface Development (5 months) at Axis Communications for their security cameras.
- Platform-Based Applications Development (1 year) at Sony Ericsson: Collaborated on Android applications, such as the calendar, and clock in a small team of 2 that expanded to eight members and 10 applications.
- Low-Level Audio Development (2 years) at ST-Ericsson: Involved development for Low Power audio, Wideband Bluetooth, and ALSA, including providing on-site support in Asia and Sweden.
- Accessibility App Development (3 months) for Netville Customer: Developed an Android application aiding visually impaired individuals.
- Test Software Development (1 year) at Sony Ericsson Mobile Communications AB: to be run on phone to test the GPS signal-to-noise redusing the test time from 30 to 4 seconds.
- Configuration Management and Development (4 years) at Ericsson AB: Initially serving as Configuration Manager, later transitioning into a developer role within the Open Platform Architecture department in addition to configuring and supporting PC-lint tool.



Mikael Vatau sleepbrunch@gmail. com (000) 111-1111

Address Rua Heliodoro 22a Lisbon Portugal

Jan 2000 - Sep 2004, Research Engineer, Robotics Lunds, University

Worked almost 5 years in multiple hardware and software projects, Maintaining of the departments computer and with development of their website.

- Network administration of the departments computers. (IRIX, Linux, and Windows)
- Assisted in developing the departments new website (news page and document repository).
- Assisted in developing the departments new website (news page and document repository).
- Implement, verify and troubleshot controller cards based on 32bit Freescale CPU for DC and Step motor control.
- Implement, verify and troubleshot controller cards based on 32bit Freescale CPU for DC and Step motor control.
- Hardware and software for controllers to be used in on a robotics arm on attached to a wheelchair (they used the CAN protocoll for communication).
- Worked with an EU project, designing and implementing the controllers and software to be used in bottle openers for physically disabled people.

Education

2009, SEMC AB (EMEA)

Linux for Embedded Systems Advanced

2008, Ericsson AB

Linux for Embedded Systems

2006, Ericsson AB

GPRS Security

2003, Malmo University

Practical English in Cross-cultural Communications

2000, SGI

IRIX System Administration

1997 - 2000, Lunds Institute of Technology

B.Sc.E. Electro Engineer

Interests

Professional

C, Linux, Security, AI

Personal

Piano, Chess, Neuroscience